Speaker: What is a bucket list?
It’s a list of things that you want to do before you die.
The expression comes from an English idiom, to kick the bucket, which means to die.
Some people make a new bucket list every year.
Others start one when they’re young, and keep on adding to it.
Others set a time limit, for example,
‘Things I want to do before I’m thirty’.
What kind of things do people put on them?
All sorts of things.
Many are to do with travel,
for example, travel to all seven continents,
go on a cruise,
see the Northern Lights,
go on a safari.
Others are about adventures,
for example, do a bungee jump,
swim with dolphins,
ride a horse on the beach.
Some involve learning new skills,
for example, learn to scuba dive,
learn to play an instrument,
learn to play chess,
go on a cookery course.
And others are just random things people would like to do,
for example, see the sun rise,
go on a blind date,
be an extra in a film,
get a tattoo,
be on TV,
see a tennis match at Wimbledon,
read a classic novel.
What would you put on your bucket list?